THE WORLD IS DIVIDED INTO TWO SIDES: ONE ABUNDANT, THE OTHER SCARCE.
EL MUNDO SE DIVIDE EN DOS LADOS: UNO ABUNDANTE, OTRO ESCASO.
AT THE AGE OF 20, EACH PERSON HAS ONE CHANCE.
A LOS 20 AׁOS, CADA PERSONA TIENE UNA OPORTUNIDAD.
THE CHOSEN ONES NEVER RETURN. THEY ARE THE 3%.
LOS ELEGIDOS NUNCA VOLVERֱN. CONSTITUYEN EL 3 POR CIENTO.
YEAR 104 OF THE PROCESS
AׁO 104 DEL PROCESO
Good morning, Michele.
Buenos dםas, Michele.
The gates to the Selection Process are open.
Las puertas del Proceso de Selecciףn estבn abiertas.
The estimated time of your walk is: 47 minutes.
El tiempo estimado de su caminata es...
Go, honey.
Adelante, hija.
I slept for maybe two hours. I was too anxious.
Dormם dos horas. Estaba demasiado ansiosa.
I doubt anyone slept last night.
Dudo que alguien haya dormido anoche.
Take care, okay?
Cuםdate, ¿sם?
THE CAUSE EVERYONE IS WORTHY
LA CAUSA TODOS LA MERECEN
"Envy and resentment have led to the rise of groups--"
"La envidia y el resentimiento llevaron al surgimiento de grupos...".
Don't dwell on that.
No insistas en eso.
My dear Nair,
Mi querida Nair,
you can say that because you are 4,000 miles away
puedes decir eso porque estבs a mבs de 6000 kilףmetros
in the safety of the Offshore.
a salvo en Alta Mar.
These terrorists are right at our doorstep.
Tenemos a estos terroristas en la puerta.
Are you going to pass? Look at her!
¿Vas a pasar? ¡Mםrenla!
You know... You know I almost made it?
Sabes... ¿Sabes que casi lo logro?
I lasted three days!
¡Durי tres dםas!
Good luck to you!
¡Buena suerte!
You're screwed! You won't last a day in there!
¡Estבs jodida! ¡No durarבs ni un dםa allם adentro!
This is as far as you can come, okay?
Hasta aquם puedes llegar, ¿sם?
Now you go home, okay?
Ahora regresa a casa, ¿entiendes?
With the faith of the Founding Couple!
¡Con la fe de la Pareja Fundadora!
With the commitment of the Founding Couple!
¡Con el compromiso de la Pareja Fundadora!
With the strength of the Founding Couple! Amen!
¡Con la fuerza de la Pareja Fundadora! ¡Amיn!
What should I do with these?
¿Quי debo hacer con esto?
Please do not forget your box numbers.
Por favor, no olviden sus nתmeros de caja.
Numbers? Fuck the numbers!
¿Nתmeros? ¡Al diablo con los nתmeros!
I'm never wearing these rags again.
Nunca mבs usarי estos harapos.
Three percent.
El tres por ciento.
Only three percent of you
Apenas el tres por ciento de ustedes
will form the select group of heroes heading to the Offshore...
serב el grupo selecto de hיroes que irב a Alta Mar.
where the Founding Couple created the perfect world.
donde la Pareja Fundadora creף el mundo perfecto.
Where there is no injustice.
Donde no existe la injusticia.
Everyone gets the same chance, and then, the place they deserve...
Todos tienen las mismas oportunidades, y el lugar que merecen.
SUPERIOR COUNCIL OFFSHORE
CONSEJO SUPERIOR DE ALTA MAR
...the Offshore or Inland.
Alta Mar o el Continente.
Or as some may say, "their side" or "our side."
O como algunos dicen, "el otro lado" o "este lado".
This Process ensures that only the best of us
Este proceso garantiza que solo los mejores de nosotros
will enjoy life on the Offshore.
disfrutemos en el Alta Mar.
But not everyone understands this.
Pero no todos entienden esto.
As you know, envy and resentment have fueled groups,
Como saben, la envidia y el resentimiento
and with populist ideas, aim to destroy everything we have achieved.
y con ideas populistas, buscan destruir todo lo que hemos logrado.
But they have always failed and will continue to fail.
Pero no lo lograron, ni lo lograrבn.
And so, welcome, everyone.
Y por tanto, sean todos bienvenidos.
Welcome, Michele.
Bienvenida, Michele.
I hope that you will do your very best, Joana.
Espero que brindes el mבximo de ti, Joana.
And that you will trust the Process, Alex.
Y que confםes en el Proceso, Alex.
Because all these years of sacrifice, Fernando,
Porque todos estos aסos de sacrificio, Fernando,
could be rewarded right here.
podrםan ser recompensados aquם.
Remember, you each create your own merit.
Recuerden, cada uno de ustedes crea su propio mיrito.
No matter what happens...
Pase lo que pase,
you deserve this.
ustedes merecen esto.
Now would be a good time to express our gratitude, don't you think?
Ahora serםa buen momento para expresar nuestro agradecimiento.
Repeat after me:
Repitan conmigo:
We are grateful for the chance...
Agradecemos la oportunidad...
-...for a better way of life.
- ...de una vida mejor.
Thank you very much.
Muchas gracias.
A NETFLIX ORIGINAL SERIES
UNA SERIE ORIGINAL DE NETFLIX
Candidates, please proceed to the interview rooms. Thank you.
Candidatos, por favor, procedan a los cuartos de entrevista. Gracias.
-Need some help? I can push you. -No, I'm good, thanks.
- ¿Necesitas ayuda? Puedo empujarte. - No, estoy bien, gracias.
-It's all good, I can help-- -Buddy, I said I don't need it.
- Estב bien, puedo... - Amigo, dije que no lo necesito.
Let them see I can get around by myself.
Deja que vean que puedo desenvolverme solo.
Sorry, man. I didn't mean to get in your way.
Lo siento, amigo. No quise interponerme en tu camino.
There's a lot of people.
Hay mucha gente.
At this rate, by the time we get to the Offshore,
A este paso, para cuando lleguemos al Otro Lado,
we'll all be 30 or 40.
tendremos 30 o 40 aסos.
Congratulations on your speech.
Felicidades por tu discurso.
You don't work here.
Tת no trabajas aquם.
My name is Aline.
Mi nombre es Aline.
I was sent to evaluate the Process this year.
Me encomendaron evaluar el Proceso este aסo.
I don't think I got that memo.
No recibם esa notificaciףn.
It was a last-minute decision.
Fue una decisiףn de תltimo momento.
It's a routine analysis of the tests and changes made over the past few years.
Es un anבlisis de rutina de las pruebas y posibilidades de los תltimos aסos.
So, I am your memo.
Soy tu notificaciףn.
Okay. But first I need to confirm your identity, all right?
Bien. Pero antes debo confirmar tu identidad, ¿sם?
Of course. If you didn't, that would have to go in my report.
Claro. Si no lo haces, tendrםa que incluirlo en mi informe.
Okay.
De acuerdo.
It'll be a pleasure having you around.
Serב un placer que me acompaסes.
Why didn't you warn me someone was coming to evaluate me?
¿Por quי no me advertiste que vendrםa alguien a evaluarme?
You were so focused on your speech, I didn't want to distract you.
Estabas tan concentrado en tu discurso, que no quise distraerte.
Besides, you and I have more important issues to discuss, Ezequiel.
Ademבs, tת y yo tenemos cosas mבs importantes que hablar, Ezequiel.
This year's Process is very important.
El Proceso de este aסo es muy importante.
No more important than any other year.
Nair, no es mבs importante que el de cualquier otro aסo.
-Nothing's changed. -Of course it has, Ezequiel.
- No hay ninguna diferencia. - Claro que sם, Ezequiel.
-How? -Are you blind?
- ¿En quי? - ¿Estבs ciego?
For the first time in a hundred years, someone was murdered here, on our side.
Por primera vez en cien aסos, mataron a alguien aquם, en nuestro lado.
-Tell me what that has-- -Don't start again.
- Dime quי... - No empieces de nuevo.
Nair, please tell me what this has to do with me and with my Process.
Nair, por favor, dime quי tiene que ver eso conmigo y mi Proceso.
You're the Process Leader,
Eres el lםder del Proceso,
responsible for everyone who comes to the Offshore.
responsable de todos los que vienen al Alta Mar.
He proved to be perfectly suitable while he was here--
ֹl demostrף ser perfectamente apto...
I'm not the one you need to convince. I'm just warning you,
No tienes que convencerme a mם. Solo te advierto,
there are those who want to blame you for the first homicide in our history.
hay gente que quiere culparte del primer homicidio en nuestra historia.
It's given Councilor Matheus and his followers leverage.
Un escבndalo que el concejal Matheus y sus seguidores aprovecharםan.
Matheus, of course.
Matheus, claro.
He wants his people to take over the Process.
Quiere que su gente tome control del Proceso.
He wants a lighter Process, a weaker Process.
ֹl quiere un Proceso mבs ligero, mבs dיbil.
To do things his way.
Hacer todo a su modo.
This is my Process.
Este es mi Proceso.
Only I can lead it.
Solamente puedo liderarlo yo.
Look, I have enough to worry about at the moment, Nair. I'm sorry.
Tengo bastante de quי preocuparme en este momento, Nair. Lo siento.
-Hi, how are you? My name is-- -Alex.
- Hola, ¿quי tal? Mi nombre es... - Alex.
Before we begin, are you aware we have no inclusion policies for--
Antes de comenzar, ¿sabes que aquם no tenemos polםtica especial para...?
Yes, I am.
Sם, lo sי.
You believe you can make it through the Process?
¿Crees que puedes pasar el Proceso?
Absolutely.
Totalmente.
I'm going to ask a sensitive question.
Harי una pregunta delicada.
When was the last time you washed your hair?
¿Cuבnto hace que no te lavas el cabello?
Since the last time I had enough water to waste.
Lo lavי la תltima vez que tuve agua que desperdiciar.
Can we go out sometime?
¿Podemos salir un dםa?
I'd like to get to know you better outside of these walls.
Quisiera conocerte mejor fuera de estos muros.
If all A's are B's, but not all B's are C's,
Si todas las A son B, pero no todas las B son C,
is it possible to have an A that's also a C?
¿es posible tener un A que tambiיn sea C?
Five seconds, okay?
Cinco segundos.
I feel like I am one of... I'm sure that I'm one of the best...
Siento que soy una de... Sי que soy una de las mejores...
Listen, Carolina... take a breath.
Escucha, Carolina... respira.
I'll give you another chance to pull yourself together.
Te darי otra oportunidad para recomponerte.
I am... I'm sure I'm part of the three percent of...
Yo soy... Estoy segura de estar dentro del tres por ciento de...
of people...
...las personas...
Elimination reason number two.
Causa de eliminaciףn nתmero dos.
What? Eliminated now? I didn't know I could be eliminated now--
¿Quי? ¿Eliminada ahora? No sabםa que me podםan eliminar ahora...
Carolina, look at yourself.
Carolina, mםrate.
If you don't believe you're worthy of passing, how can I?
Si tת misma no te crees digna de pasar, ¿por quי lo creerםa yo?
And what is your biggest weakness?
¿Y cuבl es tu mayor debilidad?
I care too much about people?
¿Preocuparme mucho por la gente?
Just kidding. But that's a good answer, right?
Solo bromeo. Pero es buena respuesta, ¿no?
It's a place where each of us can grow
Es un lugar donde cada uno pueda crecer
and reach our full potential.
y llegar a su mayor potencial.
-But it's also about helping others and-- -Enough. You answered the question.
- Pero tambiיn es ayudar a otros y... - Suficiente. Ya respondiste.
May I just add another point?
Pero ¿puedo agregar algo mבs?
I wanted to say it's about thinking of the community and--
Es importante pensar en la comunidad y en ayudar...
Have you seen this before?
¿Ya has visto esto antes?
It's graffitied everywhere.
Estב pintado por todo el lugar.
And how do you feel about the ideas of the Cause?
¿Y quי piensas sobre las ideas de la Causa?
They're just a bunch of losers who couldn't pass
Son solo unos fracasados que no pudieron pasar
and now they want to ruin everything.
y ahora quieren arruinarlo todo.
Do you know anyone who made it through?
¿Conoces a alguien que ya haya pasado?
-Luis, my boyfriend. -Let go of me!
Luis, mi novio.
-Last year? -Yes.
- ¿El aסo pasado? - Sם.
So you want to pass to be cured?
¿Quieres pasar para curarte?
I have other ambitions and goals as well as that one.
Tengo otras esperanzas y otros sueסos tambiיn.
So, you want to pass to see him again.
Quieres pasar para reencontrarte con יl.
-A romantic reunion? -No.
- ¿Encuentro romבntico? - No.
-No?
- ¿No?
He give you that necklace? If you're not a romantic, why do you wear it?
¿ֹl te regalף ese collar? Si no eres una romבntica, ¿por quי lo usas?
-It's a souvenir. -A souvenir!
- Es un recuerdo. - ¡Un recuerdo!
Did your father raise you to have faith in the Process?
¿Tu padre te crio para tener fe en el Proceso?
Yes. He's a pastor.
Sם. Es pastor.
You are one of the worst candidates I've ever interviewed.
Eres una de las peores personas que he entrevistado.
Maybe you're just the worst interviewer there is.
Quizב tת eres el peor entrevistador que hay.
Who do you think you are?
¿Quiיn te crees que eres?
Don't you realize we have candidates begging to not be eliminated?
¿No sabes que tenemos candidatos que suplican no ser eliminados?
I doubt the Offshore is interested in beggars.
No creo que a los del Otro Lado le interesen los que suplican.
-But why? -Enough. You're eliminated.
- Pero ¿por quי? - Suficiente. Estבs eliminado.
You're losing one of the best candidates.
Pierden a uno de los mejores candidatos.
You talked for 20 minutes without saying anything original.
Hablaste 20 minutos sin decir nada original.
-Please-- -Memorized bullshit.
- Por favor... - Basura memorizada.
Please, one more chance. I've dreamed of this my entire life.
Por favor, no me elimines. Soסי con esto toda mi vida.
I swear I'll shut up. Is that it? Is it because I talk too much?
Juro que me callarי. ¿Es eso? ¿Es porque hablo demasiado?
I won't say another word, I swear!
¡No hablarי mבs, lo juro!
I've been waiting for this my whole life. Don't eliminate me!
He esperado esto toda mi vida. ¡No me elimines!
Instructions on how to overcome the trauma of elimination
Las instrucciones para superar el trauma de la eliminaciףn
will be given to you while you return your uniform.
te serבn entregadas cuando devuelvas tu uniforme.
-Please! -Please, leave.
- ¡Por favor! - Por favor, vete.
-Another candidate needs this seat.
- Otro candidato necesita este lugar.
No! This is my seat! My seat! Let me go! I'm not leaving! This is my dream!
¡No! ¡Este es mi lugar! ¡Mi lugar! ¡Suיlteme! ¡No me irי! ¡Es mi sueסo!
I have to get to the Offshore!
¡Tengo que llegar al Otro Lado!
Let me go! Please! I swear, I swear, I'm good!
¡Dיjenme! ¡Por favor! Lo juro. ¡Juro que soy bueno!
You are losing the best candidate! I am the best! I am!
¡Estבn perdiendo al mejor candidato! ¡Soy el mejor! ¡Lo soy!
How do you picture the Offshore?
¿Y cףmo imaginas al Otro Lado?
I imagine... I'll be happy.
Imagino... que serי feliz.
I'll be with my family.
Estarי con mi familia.
Relaxed. Safe. Fulfilled.
Tranquilo. Seguro. Realizado.
Now, how do I picture it?
¿En cuanto a cףmo lo imagino? Lleno de בrboles,
But I know I'm going to be surprised.
Pero sי que me sorprenderי.
And don't you feel bad, Fernando? For being a burden on your father?
¿Y no te sientes mal, Fernando? ¿Al ser una carga para tu padre?
I'm not a burden. It's the opposite. He believes in me, in my abilities.
No soy una carga. Al contrario. ֹl cree en mם, en mis capacidades.
How touching.
Quי conmovedor.
Tell me something. How do you know he actually made it?
Dime una cosa. ¿Cףmo sabes que יl pasף?
He made it.
ֹl pasף.
Sometimes, candidates don't return due to unforeseen circumstances.
A veces, los candidatos no regresan debido a circunstancias imprevistas.
Unfortunate accidents.
Accidentes desafortunados.
You look very calm.
Luces muy calmado.
There's nothing to be afraid of. My family has done well in the Process.
No hay nada que temer. A mi familia le ha ido bien en el Proceso.
I have uncles, cousins... my parents.
Tengo tםos, primos... mis padres.
Do you really believe that gives you an advantage?
¿De verdad crees que eso sea una ventaja?
I am here to judge you, not your family history.
Estoy aquם para juzgarte a ti, no tu historia familiar.
I know.
Lo sי.
That's not what I meant.
No quise decir eso.
-Do you think your father loves you? -Yes.
- ¿Crees que tu padre te ama? - Sם.
-Do you love him? -Of course I do.
- ¿Tת lo amas? - Claro que sם.
So, tell me three things about him.
Dime tres cosas sobre יl.
He...
ֹl...
I don't know off the top of my head.
No se me ocurre asם de repente.
Tell me something you admire him for, something you've learned from him.
Dime algo que admiras de יl, algo que aprendiste de יl.
He...
ֹl...
You told me that you love him.
Me dijiste que lo amas.
You want to pass because your father's been telling you to pass
Quieres pasar porque tu padre te ha dicho que pases
-since you were a kid. -No, I want to pass to end my pain
desde que eras chico.
so he doesn't waste all his time on me.
Para que no desperdicie su tiempo en mם.
Look, if you keep saying the same thing, I'll eliminate you right now.
Si sigues repitiendo lo mismo, te eliminarי de inmediato.
Why do you really want to pass?
¿Por quי quieres pasar de verdad?
So I won't have a life like his.
Quiero pasar allם para no vivir asם.
APPROVED
FERNANDO CARVALHO APROBADO
-What's his name again? -Luis. Luis Ferreira.
- ¿Cuבl dijiste que es su nombre? - Luis. Luis Ferreira.
Let's find out if he really made it through.
Averigemos si realmente pasף.
Do you really want to know?
¿Quieres saberlo?
No. No, I don't care. That's not why I want to pass.
No. No me interesa. No es por eso que quiero pasar.
So, I guess that necklace doesn't mean anything, huh?
Entonces, ese collar no significa nada, ¿verdad?
If you take too long, I'll question your honesty and eliminate you.
Si demoras demasiado, dudarי de tu sinceridad y te eliminarי.
Are you gonna cry?
¿Vas a llorar?
You can move on to the next round.
Puedes pasar a la siguiente etapa.
APPROVED
MICHELE SANTANA APROBADA
You did the right thing.
Hiciste lo correcto.
He's dead.
ֹl estב muerto.
Cássia, what about the son of a bitch that was caught?
¿Cבssia? ¿Quי hay del hijo de perra que atraparon?
It's confirmed. He's with the Cause. Going by the name Jorge.
Estב confirmado. Es de la Causa. Se hace llamar Jorge.
Caught him alive, no collateral damage.
Atrapado con vida, sin daסos colaterales.
-Is that him? -Yes.
- ¿Es יl? - Sם.
-Has the interrogation started?
- ¿El interrogatorio ya comenzף?
He told us one of this year's candidates is a mole for the Cause.
Dijo que entre los candidatos de este aסo, hay un infiltrado de la Causa.
He hasn't given us a name yet, but it's just a matter of time.
Aתn no nos dio un nombre, pero es cuestiףn de tiempo.
If there is a mole among them, I need to know as soon as possible.
Si hay un infiltrado en los candidatos, quiero saberlo cuanto antes.
They captured Jorge alive.
Capturaron a Jorge con vida.
Those pigs are one step ahead of us.
Esos cerdos se nos adelantaron.
The question is, with Jorge now in their hands,
La pregunta es, con Jorge en sus manos,
what can he reveal about the moles?
¿quי puede revelar יl de los infiltrados?
-Does he know names? -No.
- ¿ֹl sabe nombres? - No.
He knew I had sent someone. He didn't have a name.
ֹl sabםa que yo habםa enviado a uno. No sabםa nombres.
Maybe a few details.
Quizב algunos detalles.
-Why did he know any details at all? -Calm down.
- ¿Por quי יl sabםa detalles? - Cבlmate.
This puts the whole operation at risk.
Esto pone en riesgo toda la operaciףn.
Calm down. We have to find out what he knew.
Cבlmate. Debemos averiguar quי sabםa יl.
I know how to run my team.
Sי cףmo dirigir mi equipo.
And I know Jorge. He's devoted to the Cause.
Y conozco a Jorge. Es devoto de la Causa.
He would never betray us!
¡Jamבs nos traicionarםa!
Take it easy. It's not about betrayal. No one can withstand their torture.
Calma. No se trata de traiciףn. Nadie puede soportar la tortura de ellos.
We have to assume that whatever he knows, the Process now knows.
Lo תnico seguro es que lo que יl sabe, ahora el Proceso tambiיn lo sabe.
Hey, Cássia. Any news?
Hola, Cבssia. ¿Alguna noticia?
He's still resisting.
ֹl aתn se resiste.
He hasn't revealed the name of the mole, but it's just a matter of time.
No ha revelado el nombre del infiltrado,
He's softening up.
Se estב ablandando.
This is bullshit! It's all bullshit!
¡Mentira! ¡Es mentira!
Motherfuckers, there are much worse candidates than me!
¡Hijos de perra, hay peores candidatos que yo!
I feel bad for them.
Me dan lבstima.
Eliminated candidates, that way.
Candidatos eliminados, por allם.
-Eliminated? That way. -Hold on...
- ¿Eliminado? Por allם. - Espere...
Yeah, but... there's nothing we can do.
Sם, pero... no podemos hacer nada.
It might be fair, but it's still sad.
Quizב sea justo, pero sigue siendo triste.
Stand back!
¡Quיdense atrבs!
Get back!
¡Atrבs!
Dr. Gisele will take care of the candidate.
La Dra. Gisele se ocuparב del candidato.
Right now we need everyone to remain calm.
En este momento, necesitamos que conserven la calma.
If you need anything, need to talk, counseling,
Si necesitan algo... Charlar, consejerםa,
we are here to help you.
estamos aquם para ayudarlos.
Don't let this interfere with the most important day of your lives.
No permitan que esto interfiera con el dםa mבs importante de su vida.
Keep going with your tests.
Continתen sus pruebas.
The Process continues this way. Follow me.
El Proceso continתa por aquם. Sםganme.
Okay.
De acuerdo.
Let's go. It's hard, but we have to move on.
Vamos, gente. Es difםcil, pero hay que seguir.
Candidates, please report to the registry scanner.
Candidatos, por favor, presיntense al escaneo de registro.
Naughty boy. Aren't you ashamed?
Chico travieso. ¿No estבs avergonzado?
-What? -Your fake registration.
- ¿Quי? - Falsificaste tu registro.
When they do it, they only use three stitches.
Cuando lo hacen, solo usan tres puntos.
I don't know what you're talking about.
No sי de quי hablas.
Let's see what the scanner says.
Veamos quי dice el escaneo.
WELCOME
BIENVENIDA
This next test is very simple.
Esta etapa es muy simple.
It evaluates your spatial logic, geometric reasoning
Evalתa su lףgica espacial, su razonamiento geomיtrico
and basic motor skills.
y la coordinaciףn bבsica.
Using these pieces, each of you will have three minutes
Con estas piezas, cada uno de ustedes tendrב tres minutos
to assemble as many cubes as possible.
para armar la mayor cantidad de cubos posible.
We expect a minimum of nine cubes.
Esperamos un mםnimo de nueve cubos.
Any less and you will be eliminated.
Si hacen menos, serבn eliminados.
And when the table turns red, it means your time is up.
Y cuando la mesa se ponga totalmente roja, el tiempo habrב acabado.
One, two, three, begin.
Uno, dos, tres, comiencen.
Thanks.
Gracias.
What's her deal? Trying to be politically correct?
¿Quי trama? No hay tiempo para ser correctos.
Doesn't she know it's every man for himself?
¿Ella no sabe que cada uno busca salvarse?
Damn it! I've asked them to fix this crap a thousand times.
¡Maldiciףn! Les pedם mil veces que arreglaran esta basura.
There we go.
Aquם vamos.
That's my cube! What the fuck?
¡Es mi cubo! ¿Quי mierda?
Time's up! Whoever has nine cubes passes.
¡Se acabף el tiempo! Quien tenga nueve cubos, pasarב.
Didn't you see him steal my cube?
¿No lo vieron robarme el cubo?
Time's up. Eight cubes. Sorry, you're eliminated.
Se acabף el tiempo. Ocho cubos. Lo siento, estבs eliminado.
-Thanks for participating. -Motherfucker!
- Gracias por participar. - ¡Maldito hijo de perra!
-Let me go! Let me go! -Take him.
- ¡Suיltenme! - Llיvenlo.
No! Let me go!
¡No! ¡Suיltenme!
Ezequiel, that kid stole the cube.
Ezequiel, ese chico se robף el cubo.
Nine, you passed.
Nueve, pasaste.
Sorry, you've been eliminated.
Lo siento, estבs eliminado.
Only eight cubes. Eliminated.
Solo ocho cubos. Eliminado.
Eliminated.
Eliminado.
Nine cubes? You passed.
¿Nueve cubos? Pasaste.
Eight plus a cube made of cubes. Nine.
Ocho mבs un cubo hecho de cubos. Nueve.
You passed as well.
Tambiיn pasaste.
Eliminated.
Eliminado.
Nine.
Nueve.
Eleven?
¿Once?
Excuse me.
Permiso.
You have to understand, while each test has an obvious goal,
Debes entender, aunque cada prueba tiene un objetivo obvio,
what's really important is what's behind them.
lo mבs importante es lo que hay detrבs.
But you may not get that yet.
Pero quizב aתn no entiendes eso.
I'm not here to judge, Ezequiel. I'm just recording the facts.
No vine a juzgar, Ezequiel. Solo registro los hechos.
She will never understand, Ezequiel.
Ella nunca entenderב, Ezequiel.
-Delicious. -It's too sweet.
- Delicioso. - Es demasiado dulce.
So, you... I heard... I heard some of the girls talking.
Eres... Escuchי hablar a las chicas.
They said you're an Álvares.
Dijeron que eres un ֱlvares.
-Your family always passes. -Yeah.
- Tu familia siempre pasa. - Sם.
So? What's the secret?
¿Y? ¿Cuבl es el secreto?
Congeniality, of course.
Simpatםa, por supuesto.
I want to thank you, really. What you did--
Quiero agradecerte. Lo que hiciste...
Forget it. It was nothing.
Olvםdalo. No fue nada.
Look who's here.
Miren quiיn llegף.
That's him.
Es יl.
Is that him?
¿Es ese?
That's so messed up.
Eso estב muy mal.
I don't understand how the Process let him pass.
No entiendo cףmo el Proceso lo dejף pasar.
I don't get the criteria.
No entiendo el criterio.
Look at him... Cheater.
Mםrenlo... Tramposo.
Go on. Keep talking about me. Go ahead. I don't care.
¡Continתen! ¡Sigan hablando de mם! ¡Adelante! No me importa.
I'm impressed how everyone here is so honest, so fair.
Me impresiona cףmo aquם son todos tan honrados, tan justos.
I just don't understand why none of you did anything.
No entiendo por quי ninguno hizo nada.
Why didn't anyone try to stop me or help the other guy?
¿Por quי ninguno intentף detenerme, o ayudar al otro?
The ones in the room. Why didn't you do anything?
Los de esta sala. ¿Por quי no hicieron nada?
Do you know why? Do you? Anyone?
¿Saben por quי? ¿Tת? ¿Alguien?
I know. Because everyone is here to make it through. Everyone.
Yo sי. Porque todos estבn aquם para pasar. Todos.
And everyone will do whatever it takes to pass.
Y todos harבn lo necesario para pasar.
I only did what everyone here will do sooner or later. That's all.
Yo solo hice lo que todos aquם harבn tarde o temprano. Es todo.
And most importantly:
Y lo mבs importante:
If you keep thinking you're better than me...
Si siguen creyיndose mejores que yo...
then you'll lose. And you'll lose to me.
...perderבn. Y perderבn conmigo.
And you'll lose to everyone here who really gets what's at stake.
Y perderבn con todos los que asumen lo que aquם hay en juego.
For real.
En serio.
What about you, big guy? What do you say?
¿Quי hay de ti, grandote? ¿Quי dices?
-Why don't you shut up? -No, I want your opinion.
- ¿Por quי no te callas? - Quiero saber tu opiniףn.
Are you saying you'd just keep your head down
¿Intentas decir que solo agacharבs la cabeza
and accept elimination without a word?
y aceptarבs la eliminaciףn sin decir una palabra?
Would you do that?
¿Harםas eso?
Would you be that stupid?
¿Serםas tan estתpido?
Take your hands off me, cheater.
No me toques, tramposo.
Take that, you son of a bitch!
Toma esto, hijo de perra.
Say something now, motherfucker!
¡Di algo ahora, hijo de perra!
Come on, loser!
¡Vamos, idiota!
Come on!
¡Vamos!
Come on! Come on!
Vamos, tramposo.
That's enough! Stop! Leave the guy alone!
¡Basta! ¡Alto! ¡Dיjenlo tranquilo!
Let him go.
Dיjenlo ir.
Let's go.
Vamos.
You don't fool me.
No me engaסas.
I know you got beat up on purpose.
Querםas que te golpearan a propףsito.
It worked. Now you have a bunch of idiots on your side.
Funcionף. Ahora tienes un grupo de idiotas de tu lado.
Actually, having a friend in the Process isn't such a bad idea.
De hecho, tener un amigo en el Proceso no es tan mala idea.
Me? Why me?
¿Yo? ¿Por quי yo?
Because if you betray me...
Porque si me traicionas...
I'll tell them your registration is fake.
...les dirי que tu registro es falso.
I know you're very busy,
Sי que estבs muy ocupado.
but if I wait until you have free time, we'll never get a chance to talk.
Pero si espero a que tengas tiempo libre, nunca podremos hablar.
I'm waiting for someone, but in the meantime, go ahead.
Estoy esperando a una persona, pero mientras tanto, adelante.
Tell me, how would you evaluate your performance over the last five years?
Dime, ¿cףmo evaluarםas tu desempeסo de los תltimos cinco aסos?
My productivity rates have reached record levels.
Mis tasas de productividad fueron rיcord.
What about adaptation? Community well-being?
¿Quי hay de la adaptaciףn? ¿El bien de la comunidad?
Your candidates haven't done well in that area.
Tus candidatos no se destacaron en esa בrea.
They didn't score well when compared to productivity rates.
No se destacaron comparados con las tasas de productividad.
Which, once again, have reached record levels.
Las cuales, repito, fueron rיcord.
Are you familiar with the concept in which selected candidates
¿Conoces el concepto en el que los candidatos seleccionados
adopt the personality of the Process Leader?
adoptan la personalidad del lםder del Proceso?
Sounds like the typical psychobabble of Councilor Matheus.
Parece tםpico palabrerםo psicolףgico del concejal Matheus.
Have you met?
¿Se conocen?
How have you been feeling?
¿Cףmo te has sentido?
I'm great. What a question. Why do you ask?
Me siento genial. ¿Por quי esa pregunta?
I'm just wondering if you ever think about your wife.
Por si alguna vez piensas en tu esposa.
-What? -Julia.
- ¿Quי? - Julia.
I never met her, but I heard what happened.
Nunca la conocם, pero supe lo que pasף.
And even from afar, it sounded painful. Even--
Y aun a la distancia, pareciף doloroso.
-I'm sorry. I'll come back later. -Come in.
- Perdףn. Volverי despuיs. - Adelante.
Aline was on her way out.
Aline ya se iba.
Actually, I would love to sit in on your meeting, if you don't mind.
De hecho, me encantarםa quedarme en su reuniףn, si no les molesta.
Please.
Por favor.
I was waiting for you.
Te estaba esperando.
I called you here to talk about the candidate who committed suicide.
Te llamי para hablar del candidato que se suicidף.
I did his interview, his evaluation,
Lo entrevistי, lo evaluי,
and he definitely showed no--
y demostrף no tener...
Denise, I'm not questioning your judgment.
Denise, no cuestiono tu criterio.
On the contrary, I'm worried about you.
Al contrario, estoy preocupado por ti.
I'm fine.
Estoy bien.
Agent Denise, sadly, suicide is not uncommon among candidates.
Funcionaria Denise, no es raro que haya suicidios entre los candidatos.
They do it out of shame.
Lo hacen por vergenza.
Because they are weak.
Porque son dיbiles.
-It's pathetic. -Pathetic.
- Es patיtico. - Patיtico.
But it takes a toll. And there's no shame in admitting that.
Pero deja su huella. Y no hay vergenza en admitirlo.
We can't ignore our feelings...
No podemos ignorar nuestros sentimientos...
or we'll never find happiness.
...o nunca seremos felices.
Of course, the suicide of a young man with no merits is a tragedy.
Claro que el suicidio de un joven sin mיrito, es una tragedia.
But you...
Pero tת...
you're a person of merit.
...eres una persona de mיrito.
That's why it's always good...
Por eso siempre es bueno...
I do that every day to remind myself that what we do
Hago eso cada dםa para recordarme que lo que hacemos
is a matter of life and death.
es cuestiףn de vida o muerte.
I understand. Perfectly.
Entiendo. Perfectamente.
Do you see things more clearly?
¿Estב todo mבs claro?
Ezequiel, I would like to thank you.
Ezequiel, quisiera agradecerte.
Everything I've learned here in such a short time
Todo lo que he aprendido aquם en tan poco tiempo,
is beyond anything I would've learned somewhere else.
supera cualquier cosa aprendida en otro lugar.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Ezequiel, we have a lead.
Ezequiel, tenemos una pista.
I want the mole's name.
Quiero el nombre del infiltrado.
It's one of two candidates.
Estב entre dos candidatas.
Michele? Bruna? Come with me, please.
¿Michele? ¿Bruna? Acompבסenme, por favor.
Thank you, Bernardo.
Gracias, Bernardo.
This way.
Por aquם.
-What's that? -Close your eyes.
- ¿Quי es eso? - Cierren los ojos.
Here. Duck your head.
Por aquם. Bajen la cabeza.
-I don't know what's happening. -Me neither.
No sי quי pasa.
Look, I know what this is about.
Escuchen, sי de quי se trata esto.
You heard me complaining about the guy who cheated in the test.
Me oyeron hablar mal del tipo que hizo trampa en la prueba.
I won't criticize the Process anymore. I've learned my lesson.
Ya no criticarי el Proceso. Aprendם mi lecciףn.
Have you two met before?
- ¿Ustedes ya se conocםan? - Sם, nosotras...
-We live on the same block. -Where do you live?
- Vivimos en la misma manzana. - ¿Dףnde vives?
I live on 7th Street, block 35, apartment 42.
En la calle 7, manzana 35, departamento 42.
Same block, apartment 12.
Misma manzana, departamento 12.
We received some information that a mole working for the Cause
Nos informaron que hay un infiltrado de la Causa
lives on that same street, on the same block.
que vive en esa calle y esa manzana.
How do you know that?
¿Cףmo saben esas cosas?
The fact is, we know that one of you sitting here is the mole.
El hecho es que sabemos que una de ustedes es la infiltrada.
I just don't know which one.
No sי cuבl.
So, I have three minutes to find out
Tengo tres minutos para descubrir
who is with the Cause and who is innocent.
quiיn es de la Causa, y quiיn es inocente.
And if I can't figure it out, the recommended step
Y si no lo logro descubrir, el procedimiento recomendado
is that I kill both of you.
es que las mate a ambas.
-Ma'am-- -There must be a mistake.
- Seסora. - Debe haber un error.
I don't know anyone in the Cause.
No conozco a nadie de la Causa.
-Me neither. -We know each other.
- Yo tampoco. - Nos conocemos.
I swear to you--
Le juro que...
Sit down! Stay back, please.
Sentadas. Atrבs, por favor.
-This is a test. -No, unfortunately, it's not.
- Esto es una prueba. - Lamentablemente, no.
I'm innocent! I'm-- I am not with the Cause!
¡Soy inocente! ¡No estoy con la Causa!
-I don't know anyone in the Cause! -Me neither.
- ¡No conozco a nadie de la Causa! - Yo tampoco.
-I am not with the Cause. -Neither am I.
- Yo no soy de la Causa. - Tampoco yo.
-Are you accusing me? -Of course not!
- ¿Me acusas? - ¡Claro que no!
But she said it's one of us and I'm saying it's not me.
Pero ella dijo que es una de nosotras y no soy yo.
-It's not me, either! -Bruna, you know me.
- ¡Tampoco yo! - Bruna, me conoces.
-You know I'm not with the Cause! -I can't sit here listening to excuses.
- ¡Sabes que no soy de la Causa! - No puedo sentarme a oםr excusas.
I need a confession, do you understand?
Necesito una confesiףn, ¿entienden eso?
-Bruna, please... -It's not me.
- Bruna, por favor... - No soy yo.
Whoever is with the Cause and believes that they're a savior...
Quien sea de la Causa y se considere una salvadora,
this is your chance to do something useful for society and save someone's life.
es su oportunidad de hacer algo תtil para la sociedad y salvar la vida de alguien.
Because you will die anyway and take an innocent person with you.
Porque morirב de todos modos, y se llevarב a una inocente con ella.
Bruna, please...
Bruna, por favor,
if you are with the Cause, save my life.
si eres de la Causa, salva mi vida.
I'm not with the Cause, Michele.
No soy de la Causa, Michele.
-I'm not. -Then they have the wrong information.
- No soy yo. - Ellos tienen informaciףn errףnea.
Of course they do!
¡Claro que sם!
What are we going to do, for God's sake?
¿Quי vamos a hacer, por Dios?
-This isn't happening-- -We're gonna die.
- No puede ser... - Vamos a morir...
We're already dead.
Ya estamos muertas.
What are we gonna do?
¿Quי haremos?
Listen...
Escucha...
we have one way out.
...tenemos una salida.
We have to attack this woman.
Debemos atacar a esta mujer.
-We have to attack her. -We can't attack her. She's armed.
- Tenemos que atacarla. - No podemos. Estב armada.
If we get her gun, she'll--
Podemos tomar su arma.
She won't.
No lo harב.
It's you and me.
Somos tת y yo.
Two against one.
Dos contra uno.
Bruna, when she comes back, we'll take her gun.
Bruna, cuando ella vuelva, tomaremos su arma.
We're gonna run away from the Process.
Escaparemos del Proceso.
We're gonna run away.
Escaparemos.
Bruna, we can't die now. I don't wanna die.
Bruna, no podemos morir ahora. No quiero morir.
Look at me.
Mםrame.
Trust me, okay?
Confםa en mם.
I'll give you a signal and we'll attack her.
Te darי una seסal y la atacaremos.
Your time is up.
Se acabף su tiempo.
Who's going to confess?
¿Quiיn va a confesar?
Why do you want to make it through?
¿Por quי quieres pasar?
I have a lot to offer the Offshore.
Tengo mucho que ofrecer al Otro Lado.
If I have enough merit, you will see it in me.
Si tengo mיrito suficiente, lo verבn en mם.
Your boyfriend gave you this.
Tu novio te regalף esto.
What boyfriend? I don't have a boyfriend.
¿Quי novio? No tengo novio.
I know.
Lo sי.
It's for the interviewer.
Es para el entrevistador.
You have to say exactly what the Process wants to hear.
Tienes que decir lo que el Proceso quiere oםr.
It was Ezequiel.
Fue Ezequiel, ¿no?
-Ezequiel killed my brother. -Don't think about that.
- Ezequiel matף a mi hermano. - No pienses en eso.
You won't get anywhere near Ezequiel.
No te acercarבs a Ezequiel.
And if you do, run. Stay away from him.
Y si lo haces, corre. Alיjate de יl.
I'm sorry you had to see that. Move aside.
Lamento que hayas tenido que ver eso. Apבrtate.
Get up.
Levבntate.
Get over there.
Ponte allם.
I think I can trust you.
Creo que puedo confiar en ti.
I got this.
Ya entendם.
That's what my brother used to say.
Es lo que solםa decir mi hermano.
Whenever I asked him for anything, he'd say, "I got this."
Cada vez que le pedםa algo, יl decםa: "Ya entendם".
You really loved him.
Lo amabas mucho.
He was five years older than me and...
Era cinco aסos mayor que yo y...
when our parents died...
...cuando nuestros padres murieron...
Revenge isn't about killing Ezequiel.
La venganza no reside en matar a Ezequiel.
It's destroying their entire world.
Es destruir todo su mundo.
You have to act as if you blindly believe in the Process.
Tienes que actuar como si creyeras ciegamente en el Proceso.
Act completely naive. Tell me... can you cry?
Actuar totalmente ingenua. Dime... ¿puedes llorar?
Yes.
Sם.
That will be useful.
Eso serב תtil.
Are you gonna cry?
¿Vas a llorar?
The key is to hold back your tears. Fight them back.
La clave es aguantar las lבgrimas. Resistirse a ellas.
That's what gets to them.
Eso es lo que los emociona.
I got this.
Ya entendם.
Michele, what just happened has to stay between us.
Michele, lo que acaba de ocurrir tiene que quedar entre nosotras.
A mole for the Cause is not the concern of the other candidates.
Un infiltrado en la Causa no es asunto de los demבs candidatos.
Where were you?
¿Dףnde estuviste?
Michele, what happened?
Michele, ¿quי pasף?
Subtitle translation by João Neto
Traducciףn: Viviana Cilurzo